

Kalyan Chokkarapu

- √ Valparaisostraße 17C, 22761 Hamburg,
- +4915163266330
- kalyanqa4@gmail.com
- nttp://linkedin.com/in/kalyan-c-b279946a

PERSONAL STATEMENT

Having 9 plus years of extensive experience as Quality Engineer in Manual, Automation, API Testing, Performance Testing, ETL/ DWH testing Big Data Testing. Experienced in testing Web based & Mobile applications. Expert in using automation tools like Selenium and JMeter Well versed with automation frameworks like TestNG, JUnit and Hybrid. Extensive experience of agile methodologies and Scrum process. I do possess German residence permit VISA valid up to April 2022.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Tools & Frame works Selenium Webdriver, TestNG, Junit, Extent reports, Auto IT,

Apache POI, Postman, Docker, JMeter & Load Runner.

Languages Java, Python, JavaScript and C

ETL and Reporting Tools Informatica, SSRS, Reltio, ARTIS, SAS VA, CDS, ZS Edge, Ultra Compare Pro,

MicroStratagy, QlikView and Qlik Sense.

Build ToolsMaven, SVN, GithubReportingJIRA, HP ALM and BugzillaDatabasesSQL Server, Oracle, HiveQL

Operating systems Windows & Linux

Domain Knowledge Life Sciences, HealthCare, clinical trials, Retail Banking and Insurance.

WORK EXPERIENCE

04/05/2020-25/08/2020

Quality Engineer - Card Payments Wirecard Technologies, Munich(Germany)

- Review requirements, design, develop, plan and implement test cases, test strategies covering acquiring
 transactions, billing and settlement related data into data warehouse using Pentaho for ETL data integration
 and present that data for insights using Micro Strategy as a front-end enterprise business intelligence
 analytics application in form of reports and dashboards.
- Development of synthetic test data generation automation framework for credit card and alternative payments transactions to test different trends and scenarios.
- Review existing QA processes and assist/suggest in establishing new standards and processes based on industry trends and best practices.
- Possess good exposure to Continuous Integration / Continuous Delivery process/set ups (CI/CD)
- Development of Jenkins jobs for database schema creation and extracting, importing data.
- Writing complex sql queries for data troubleshooting & data transformation, loading verification.
- Ability to create reports and visual, interactive dossiers, design facts and attributes in Micro Strategy
- Writing, reviewing test documentation. Presenting test result.

06/11/2018-13/02/2019

Senior Test Lead

Deloitte India Pvt Ltd, Hyderabad (India)

- Interacting with Stake Holders, Project team, Business Team, UAT users, Business analysts and E2E designers, Application Support Groups.
- User acceptance testing, End to End testing, Regression Testing of Web and Mobile applications.
- Extensive experience of creating and managing test automation scripts using Selenium web driver for end to end testing.
- Performing Rest API testing using Postman to test Backend calls.
- Possess good exposure to Continuous Integration / Continuous Delivery process/set ups (CI/CD)
- Bugs tracking, reproducing and verification in the correct test environment.
- Responsible for Quality Assurance of the developed applications.
- Providing 1st and 2nd level support to the end customers using JIRA Helpdesk.
- Involved in the operational tasks, including monitoring the live running systems and environments.

- Reporting the Incident to team in case of any failure in the live system or product.
- Develop guides and documentation for JIRA features and best practices.
- Writing new test cases and improving the previously written test cases, user stories.
- Participated in daily stand-up meetings, sprint planning, review meetings and took active part in retrospective by providing necessary feedback.
- Prepared Test Summary Reports, daily execution reports, weekly status reports, & UAT Handover reports.
- Executing Sanity and Scope items in UAT and Production environments for each release.
- Support multiple releases Major, maintenance & Patch releases.
- Good experience in accessing incident management tools like Service Now and Cherwell for production support tickets.
- Assigning production support tickets to Dev Team and providing user access to the newly joined client team.
- Lead the test engineers for better quality, helped client services team for recreating user reported issues and provide training on new functionalities, created various user manuals for customers.

14/03/2018-31/10/2018

Sr Consultant MSR COSMOS Pvt Ltd, Hyderabad (India)

- Worked closely with business teams to ensure that all needs were met and all desired functions were implemented correctly.
- Created and executed test cases with detailed steps and validation results Used HP ALM to write and
 execute detailed test cases as per the business requirements and functional specifications.
- Involved in Smoke Testing, Functional testing, Re-testing, Regression testing, Functional Testing, System Testing and Performance Testing.
- Sent out daily and weekly testing status reports to keep team updated on project.
- Logged defects using ALM and work with business analyst and developer to follow the defect cycle.
- Conducted meetings to triage and resolve defects and issues for each sprint.
- Involved in Performance Testing using Load Runner.
- Creating load runner Scripts and Scenarios. Enhance Load Runner scripts and Execute Load Tests.
- Individual will be developing and managing the load runner test scripts.
- Customize the Parameterization. Monitor and Analyse Tests and Prepare Test Reports.
- Led the UAT effort in ensuring that all aspects of agile testing were met by attending daily scrum meetings and keeping an up to date log of tasks for each team member.
- Conducted thorough end to end testing to ensure the overall product met all requirements and processed through various platforms successfully.

05/03/2010-09/03/2018

QA Lead/ SR. QA Analyst/QA Analyst Paragon Solutions(Part of CGI), Bangalore (India)

- Interacting with Stake Holders, Project team, Business Team, UAT users, Business analysts and E2E designers, Application Support Groups.
- Created and implemented test plan and test strategy document outlining the scope, objectives, timeline and focus of software testing effort for functional, regression and user acceptance testing.
- Executed test cases manually to make sure that the functionality is working as expected, analysed errors, reported defects to development team, helped development team to recreate/troubleshoot the defects and documented the test results.
- Designed and developed automation framework for smoke and regression suite using Selenium WebDriver with Page object model approach and TestNG (HYBRID framework) to replace manual regression test cases.
- Automated the Scenarios which include integration testing to make sure new feature doesn't break the
 existing functionality.
- Responsible for Execution of test scripts and maintenance of the Test Suites by debugging fixing issues.

29/10/2020 Page **2** of **3**

- Involved in data base testing to check whether the fields in the UI/frontend forms are mapped consistently with the corresponding fields in the DB table.
- Used Github to check-in the automation test scripts and executed the automation scripts using Jenkins/Maven plug in.
- Created different Jenkin jobs to run automation scripts on different environments like QA, Staging, UAT and Production.
- Involved in daily stand-up meetings, sprint planning, review meetings and took active part in retrospective by providing necessary feedback.
- Prepared Test concept documents, daily execution reports, weekly status reports & UAT Handover reports.
- Proficient in backend testing including writing SQL, Oracle and HiveQL Queries for Backend testing and validating business rules.
- Support multiple releases Major, maintenance & Patch releases.
- Resource On-boarding, assignment and tracking, resource development & training.

LANGUAGES

- English Native or Bilingual Proficiency
- German Beginner

EDUCATION QUATIFICATIONS

31/12/2001-31/12/2003 Master of Business Administration. Kakatiya University, Warangal (INDIA)

16/03/1998-31/03/2001 Bachelor Degree in computer science Kakatiya University, Warangal (INDIA)